# Seva Deriushkin

# Front-end **Developer**

Vrestaby 1110 Landvetter, 43893

Phone: +46 79 306 4348 Email: seva.deriushkin@gmail.com

Links: Github

#### About Me

I dream big and I want to deliver real value to people. I want to build software to promote self-sovereignty and resist censorship. I want to continue pushing myself to learn new things and expand my expertise to new areas. Aside from work, I run the YouTube channel called New Tonality where I combine my expertise in music, physics and software development to deepen our understanding of music theory.

#### Education

#### **Ural State University**

#### MCs in Physics

September 2009 - August 2015, Yekaterinburg

Studied conductivity of doped HgSe in high magnetic fields and low temperatures to understand scattering of electrons in semimetals for applications in spintronics.

#### **Technical Skills**

Languages: TypeScript, Kotlin, Python, Ruby, HTML, CSS

Frameworks: Next.js (React), Vue.js, SvelteKit, Solid Start, Jetpack Compose, Django, Ruby on Rails

Testing: Cypress, Vitest, Jest, Pytest, RSpec

Other: Storybook, Prisma, Redux, REST, GraphQL, Github Actions

Aspirations: Bitcoin Lightning, Rust, C++

**Work Experience** 

#### Stendahls Reklambyrå AB / Front-end Developer

November 2021 - Present, Gothenburg, Sweden

One of the best ad / consultancy agencies in the world with big clients here in Sweden such as Volvo Group, Husqvarna and Lansforsakringar. My role is front-end development in React + TypeScript and Vue3.

### Adaptive Labs Nordics AB / Full-stack Developer

July 2021 - November 2021, Gothenburg, Sweden

A company we formed with a bunch of friends to do website development. We delivered two projects in React front-end + Ruby on Rails back-end after which I went on into the industry to seek bigger projects, professional growth and to aquire wisdom.

# **Internet Freelancer / Podcast Audio Editing**

January 2020 - April 2021, Gothenburg, Sweden

Applied my expertise in audio recording and editing to help some clients on Peopleperhour platform. Sample of my work is the first season of Blagbook the Podcast on Spotify (link).

# **Russian Academy of Science / Researcher**

September 2013 - December 2019, Yekaterinburg, Russia

After University I joined a group that was researching spin polarization and conductivity of semimetals as an experimental physicist. We were measuring electronic properties of HgSe crystals in near absolute zero temperatures at very high magnetic fields to understand the physics of spin polarization for possible applications in the industry. The result of the work were several publications in peer-reviewed journals.